<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Catel docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Catel docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fast member invoker</title>
      <link>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/fastmemberinvoker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/fastmemberinvoker/</guid>
      <description>The FastMemberInvoker is a low-level compiled expression tree member invocation wrapper. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of buzz-words, but it means that this is a wrapper to get or set properties and fields of objects dynamically in the fastest way possible.
More documentation should be written in the future
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property helper</title>
      <link>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/propertyhelper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/propertyhelper/</guid>
      <description>The PropertyHelper class is a reflection-based helper class to get or set properties on classes. This class is used by Catel as a fall-back mechanism to use reflection in case cached expression trees are not supported.
For better performance, use the FastMemberInvoker instead
Setting or getting properties of objects In lots of cases, you need to possibility to set or get properties of an object via reflection. This behavior is implemented in the PropertyHelper class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type cache</title>
      <link>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/typecache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.catelproject.com/vnext/catel-core/reflection/typecache/</guid>
      <description>The TypeCache is the centralized cache by Catel for type information. It should be used by any class to gather type information since most of the calls are being cached by Catel.
Getting types without versioning Sometimes you know what type to get and what assembly it is living in. However, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be version-dependent by specifying the fully qualified assembly name. By using the TypeCache.GetType method, it is possible to get a type by only the assembly name (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
